<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic on Academic</title>
    <link>https://leeaburton.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Academic on Academic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>World Data</title>
      <link>https://leeaburton.github.io/project/project-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 14:58:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeaburton.github.io/project/project-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while ago a policy change in the US prompted coders and scientists to start downloading and collecting NASA data. I ended up with a huge repository of data for land elevation for the entire globe. It was too large to practically work with and it didn&amp;rsquo;t relate directly to my own research so it has been sidelined for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I made this site there is a place I can put the results and update my slow but steady progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://leeaburton.github.io/img/Scandanavia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image above was the largest plot of the data that I was able to run on my laptop for a long time. At last I think I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to make the data workable by converting format and coarsegraining heavily. So hopefully in the coming weeks I can make some pretty plots and create working model for the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have no real goal of what to do with this info but I think it could be the basis of a lot of interesting stuff in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; update 27 March 2018 &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok it seems I was finally able to get the ball rolling. This is the first major chunk of data I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to extract and work with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://leeaburton.github.io/img/Globe_NE_full.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully it is recognisable as the North-east quarter of the globe, as defined by the prime miridian and equator. It&amp;rsquo;s enough to play around with for now but of course i still want to work on getting the full world data&amp;hellip; hopefully not too long now!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://leeaburton.github.io/post/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 14:35:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeaburton.github.io/post/post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a while I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to make somewhere that could keep useful info or host unofficial side projects. Thanks to Hugo and github i&amp;rsquo;ve been able to put this site together quite easily. For now the plan is to have posts where i can keep snippets i&amp;rsquo;ve found useful on certain topics, for example using Blender to create snazzy images, and projects where ideas can be built up bit by bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to keep redundancy to a minimum, so if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for papers head over to google scholar, random thoughts head over to twitter etc. Here will just be for stand-alone work stuff&amp;hellip; apologies in advanced if it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes a little rough around the edges! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Site</title>
      <link>https://leeaburton.github.io/post/post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 14:35:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeaburton.github.io/post/post-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m always forgetting how to code. It&amp;rsquo;s not a great trait for someone who&amp;rsquo;s entire career depends on it. As i said in my first post I want this site to be a place to keep the kind of snippets I always forget. So to begin I&amp;rsquo;ll put here the info relevant for the site itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, this site is built by Hugo and not Jekyll. I installed Hugo with &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;, which is a great package manager for mac computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write the files on my computer, which are easy to read, modify and create. Then Hugo compiles them for me into a &amp;lsquo;public&amp;rsquo; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These changes can be viewed locally before i make anything public, so I can check I didn&amp;rsquo;t do too much damage!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be done by typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and then opening &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;localhost:1313&lt;/a&gt; in my web browser&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site&amp;rsquo;s progress is easily documented, tracked and kept transparent by github. Github also provides the domain, as you can see from the address bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I use Hugo to build the files, I go to the public directory, add the changes, comment on the changes and push to the repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commands for this are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd public&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git commit -m &amp;ldquo;explanation of most recent changes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it takes about 10 minutes before the site updates to the most recent version.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
