<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic on Academic</title>
    <link>https://leeaburton.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Academic on Academic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Light</title>
      <link>https://leeaburton.github.io/project/project-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 14:58:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeaburton.github.io/project/project-light/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is another side-project based on data from NASA. I found the information for amount of sunlight at each point on the planet for latitude and longitude. I cross referenced this with the coordinates for cities in the world to see which is the sunniest place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to factor in electricity cost and use that to find the best location in the world to put solar panels in terms of profit return, rather than for example some amazing work been done in Africa on an almost charity basis. A combination of expensive electricity and intense sunlight was the most desirable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One problem is the available data for electricity cost is really hard to come by in a consistant way. Another problem I found when I pitched this idea to a mock panel of investors, is that political instability is a huge problem for something like this. The top 2 or 3 locations returned by my code were in relatively volatile parts of the world and the panel were not keen. Needless to say I did not win that competition :p&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now my plan is a little different. In Project: World I&amp;rsquo;m developing the data for world land area. This can then be overlayed with the data I have here for available sunlight to create an estimate of global solar energy potential. This is just one straight-forward idea. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that by putting these resources side by side on this sight I can form separate but complimentary projects to build towards something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TO DO: make a plot of the solar intensity data as a grid.
TO DO: tidy up the script and put it on github linked here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Data</title>
      <link>https://leeaburton.github.io/project/project-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 14:58:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeaburton.github.io/project/project-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while ago a policy change in the US prompted coders and scientists to start downloading and collecting NASA data. I ended up with a huge repository of data for land elevation for the entire globe. It was too large to practically work with and it didn&amp;rsquo;t relate directly to my own research so it has been sidelined for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I made this site there is a place I can put the results and update my slow but steady progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://leeaburton.github.io/img/Scandanavia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image above was the largest plot of the data that I was able to run on my laptop for a long time. At last I think I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to make the data workable by converting format and coarsegraining heavily. So hopefully in the coming weeks I can make some pretty plots and create working model for the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have no real goal of what to do with this info but I think it could be the basis of a lot of interesting stuff in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; update 27 March 2018 &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok it seems I was finally able to get the ball rolling. This is the first major chunk of data I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to extract and work with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://leeaburton.github.io/img/Globe_NE_full.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be recognisable as the North-east quarter of the globe, as defined by the prime miridian and equator. It&amp;rsquo;s enough to play around with for now but of course i still want to work on getting the full world data&amp;hellip; hopefully not too long now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;update: OK, this is a way clearer representation of what I have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://leeaburton.github.io/img/Globe_NE_BW.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is found by splitting the data into black and white. White for any point where the elevation is zero with respect to sea level and black for anything higher than that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Site</title>
      <link>https://leeaburton.github.io/post/post-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 14:35:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeaburton.github.io/post/post-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m always forgetting how to code. It&amp;rsquo;s not a great trait for someone who&amp;rsquo;s entire career depends on it. As i said on my homepage I want this site to be a place to keep the kind of snippets I always forget. So to begin I&amp;rsquo;ll put here the info relevant for the site itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, this site is built by Hugo and not Jekyll. I installed Hugo with &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;, which is a great package manager for mac computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write the files on my computer, which are easy to read, modify and create. Then Hugo compiles them for me into a &amp;lsquo;public&amp;rsquo; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These changes can be viewed locally before i make anything public, so I can check I didn&amp;rsquo;t do too much damage!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be done by typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and then opening &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;localhost:1313&lt;/a&gt; in my web browser&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site&amp;rsquo;s progress is easily documented, tracked and kept transparent by github. Github also provides the domain, as you can see from the address bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I use Hugo to build the files, I go to the public directory, add the changes, comment on the changes and push to the repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commands for this are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd public&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git commit -m &amp;ldquo;explanation of most recent changes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it takes about 10 minutes before the site updates to the most recent version.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
