<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic on Academic</title>
    <link>https://leeaburton.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Academic on Academic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>First Project</title>
      <link>https://leeaburton.github.io/project/first-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 14:58:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeaburton.github.io/project/first-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;test first project :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://leeaburton.github.io/post/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 14:35:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeaburton.github.io/post/post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a while I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to make somewhere that could keep useful info or host unofficial side projects. Thanks to Hugo and github i&amp;rsquo;ve been able to put this site together quite easily. For now the plan is to have posts where i can keep snippets i&amp;rsquo;ve found useful on certain topics, for example using Blender to create snazzy images, and projects where ideas can be built up bit by bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to keep redundancy to a minimum, so if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for papers head over to google scholar, random thoughts head over to twitter etc. Here will just be for stand-alone work stuff&amp;hellip; apologies in advanced if it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes a little rough around the edges! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Site</title>
      <link>https://leeaburton.github.io/post/post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 14:35:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeaburton.github.io/post/post-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m always forgetting how to code. It&amp;rsquo;s a great trait for someone who&amp;rsquo;s entire career depends on it. As i said in my first post I want this site to be a place to keep the kind of snippets I always forget. So to begin with I document here the info relevant for the site itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, this site is built by Hugo and not Jekyll. I installed Hugo with Homebrew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I modify the files on my computer, which are easy to read, modify and create. And then Hugo compiles them for me into a &amp;lsquo;public&amp;rsquo; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s progress is easily documented, tracked and kept transparent by github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;github also provides the website domain, as you can see from the address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after I use Hugo to build the files, I go to the public directory, add the changes, comment on the changes and push to the repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the commands for this are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hugo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cd public&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;git add .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;git commit -m &amp;ldquo;explanation of most recent changes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;git push&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
